Hello and welcome to knowledgehut.
In the IT Industry, many people get confused between DevOps and Agile.
In this DevOps vs Agile video, we will be trying to uncover some of the major differences
between both of them.
So let us begin.
First, What they are?
While Agile refers to an iterative approach which focuses on collaboration, customer feedback,
and small, rapid releases.
DevOps is considered a practice of bringing development and operations teams together.
What are their Purpose?
While Agile helps to manage complex projects.
DevOps’ central concept is to manage end-to-end engineering processes.
Task Agile process focuses on constant changes.
DevOps focuses on constant testing and delivery.
Implementation Agile method can be implemented within a range
of tactical frameworks like safe and scrum.
The primary goal of DevOps is to focus on collaboration, so it doesn't have any commonly
accepted framework.
Team skill set Agile development emphasizes training all
team members to have a wide variety of similar and equal skills.
DevOps divides and spreads the skill set between the development and operation teams.
Team size Small Team is at the core of Agile.
As smaller is the team, the fewer people on it, the faster they can move.
Devops has relatively larger team size as it involves all the stakeholders
Feedback In Agile, Feedback is given by the customer.
In DevOps(In DevOps repeated twice) While Feedback comes from the internal team.
Emphasis Agile emphasizes on software development,
the process ends at the development stage and then there is no focus on operations.
DevOps emphasizes not only on the development process but also on the operation or monitoring
process.
It takes ready-to-release software and deploys it in a reliable and secure manner.
Goal Agile addresses the gap between customer need
and development & testing teams.
Devops addresses the gap between development + testing and operation.
Focus Agile focuses on functional and non-function
readiness.
Devops focuses on operational and business readiness.
Importance Developing software is inherent to Agile.
Developing, testing and implementation all are equally important in DevOps.
Speed vs. Risk Teams using Agile support rapid change, and
on a robust application structure.
In the DevOps method, the teams must make sure that the changes which were made
to the architecture never develop a risk to the entire project.
Quality Agile produces better applications suites
with the desired requirements.
It can easily adapt according to the changes made on time, during the project life.
DevOps, along with automation and early bug removal, contributes to creating better quality.
Developers need to follow Coding and Architectural best practices to maintain quality standards.
Advantage Agile offers a shorter software development
cycle and improved defect detection.
DevOps supports Agile release cycle.
So these were some differences between DevOps and Agile.
We hope this video helped you to understand both of them.
Don’t forget subscribe to our channel for more such videos and visit our website courses
which can give a leap to your career.